Orlando, FL 32824 | 407-932-8226 <u>adamseanflorez@gmail.com</u> | <u>Linkedin.com/in/adamflorez/</u> Willing to Travel

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Software engineer graduating with Bachelor's degree in June 2022 and offering combination of technical projects and software development experience. Well-honed communications and interpersonal skills to work with diverse, crossfunctional teams and managers. Record of contributing to business improvements, performance, and operations. Enjoys developing software, producing innovative products, and working with complex data in fast-paced environments.

KEY QUALIFICATIONS

Software Engineering & Programming | IT Service Desk Operations & Reporting | Project Management
Object-oriented Programming | Team Management | Documentation | Compliance | Research & Data Analysis
Dashboard & Visualization Creation | Technical Solutions | Policies & Procedures Implementation
Coding & Testing | Software Life Cycle | Web Applications

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE & SKILLS

Languages: HTML; CSS; JavaScript; Python; C#; and ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS | **Databases:** MySQL; MongoDB; Neo4j **Software:** Unix; Linux; Adobe Creative Suite; Microsoft Office Suite: Word, Excel, PowerPoint and Power BI; Internet

Explorer; Google Chrome; Google Drive/Apps; GIT; AWS

Security: VPN; WPA; WPA2; SSL; TCP/IP; OSI Model/Internet Suite Protocol; HTTP; 802.11

Hardware: Network Infrastructure; Servers; Cabling; Coaxial Cables; Power Supplies; Hard Disk; Cooling Fans;

Motherboards; CPU; RAM; CD/DVD Drives; Graphic Card in AGP Bus; and more

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AdventHealth, Altamonte Springs, FL | October 2018 - Present

Information Technology (IT) Business Analyst | Promoted from Service Desk Analyst → Work onsite and remote.

—AdventHealth is healthcare system headquartered in Altamonte; 45 hospital campuses, 35 urgent-care facilities, and 15 skilled-nursing facilities in 9 states; 83K+ Employees; 5M+ patients cared for annually.

Promoted to lead and manage business projects providing senior managers and executives with analytics, metrics, and improvement recommendations on service desk operation with 90 employees delivering IT solutions enterprise-wide. Perform broad range of business analysis, reporting, and IT functions with multiple information and communication systems. Work independently and with teams. Interface with internal customers / stakeholders. Share information, present at meetings, and demonstrate best practices. Produce creative reports; advise management on IT solutions.

- Promoted for solving problems, managing projects well, and highlighting data with solutions on reports to improve service desk operations.
- Improved performance and reduced payroll costs by creating reports showing times of day IT agents are most needed and number of abandoned calls that allowed management to change schedules; used MS Power BI and Python to create reports, data models, charts, and graphs for management to drive cost savings for organization.
- Identified cost savings of 310+ hours of payroll, reported trend, and presented to manager that service desk employees signing in on phones did not promptly start work; new policies implemented to drive changes.
- Solved broad range of IT tickets, tested / maintained software, and promoted optimal use of various technology throughout healthcare operations; shared knowledge and ensured compliance of service level agreements (SLAs).

Earle C. Clements Job Corps Center, Morganfield, KY | December 2017 – October 2018 Information Technology (IT) Field Technician

—US's largest educational and job training program for motivated young adults for successful careers in fast-growing industries.

Relocated and seized opportunity to gain IT skills with hands-on program. Completed IT training program ahead of schedule and received full-time, paid position as IT Field Technician setting up, installing, and managing 1K+ new and existing computers and equipment. Provided troubleshooting, repaired equipment, and restored files. Improved network issues, such as LAN hardware and connectivity. Monitored systems, analyzed performance levels, maintained backup and security, and interacted with vendors and internal customers. Managed concurrent technical projects; investigated, addressed, and documented information technology issues.

- Built relationships across departments working with faculty, staff, and students to solve IT problems; installed cable, computers, and equipment, including setup computers, added hard drives, installed security software, and completed IT projects.
- Configured network to eliminate signal dropping from wireless connection interrupting operations and negatively impacting training programs; installed CAT5e cabling, Cisco switches, and terminated ends on 110 blocks to enhance capabilities.
- Performed various IT hardware functions, including solving operating systems issues with team and re-imaged computers.

Level Solar, Ronkonkoma, NY | September 2014 – April 2017

Site Survey Manager | Employee Trainer

Level Solar was a privately-held, residential solar installer; 100+ Employees; closed in September 2017.

Managed survey crew of 5 employees, interviewed candidates, trained employees, and led projects to completion.

- Created system that increased number of surveys conducted daily from 6 to 8-10; minimized customers' concerns answering technical questions, and provided positive customer experiences as project point-of-contact.
- Achieved / maintained 100% safety record of no major roof incidents with robust employee training program.

Wireless Sounds, LTD, Ronkonkoma, NY | June 2011 - September 2014

Operations Team Lead

—Sound designs and installation of production equipment: audio and lighting solutions; rental, repair, and equipment sales.

Led complex, audio-visual installation projects. Managed teams of 10 employees and budgets. Installed software, cables, and equipment. Maintained e-commerce sales and interacted with business clients and commercial accounts.

• Delivered projects on time and within budget with zero safety issues while satisfying clients' requirements.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Web Development and Design — Full Sail University, Orlando, FL

Expected Graduation: June 2022; Honors: National Society of Collegiate Scholars; GPA: 3.6 / 4.0

Relevant Courses: Software Engineering; Project and Portfolio I–VI; Web Architecture Web Development I, II & III; Interfaces and Usability; Interface Programming; Application Development; Database Systems; Advanced Server-Side Languages; Programming for Web Applications; Cloud Application Development; Application Integration and Security; Content Management System Development; Connected Devices and Applications; Secure Application Development

Projects: Gained experience in software development and coded in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, C#, ReactJS, MySQL, and MongoDB throughout courses; planned, designed, developed, tested, documented, and improved software.

Selected Software Development and Engineering Projects:

- News App Developed ReactJS application accessing free News API; fetched data from search input and shows
 top stories on specified topic; users click on stories for summary and link to full article. Coded and used ReactJS,
 CSS, and JavaScript software languages and gained experience in cross-origin resource sharing (CORS).
- Record Lift Workout application created using API workouts and images; users search and add workouts to
 enhance experience and use of app. Languages used: HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Used Fetch API and Vanilla
 JavaScript (JS). During courses, gained knowledge on design patterns, including MVC and Simple Factory.
- Cryptocurrency Tracker Developed real-time cryptocurrency tracker with filtered search. Users start typing, and app filters results. Languages used: ReactJS and CSS. API used: Coin Gecko. Demonstrated program to class.
- Music Player Created music player with Vanilla JavaScript and used static data. Languages used: HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Learned refactoring and clean code. Presented project and demonstrated to users.